Are you all having a wonderful Sunday?
Happy Mother's Day?
Is it?
I didn't realize.
It may be different in Denmark.
I gotta check on that.
Cheers.
Is it the sound from heaven?
Wait, do I still have the thing on?
Haha!
It was on from last time, I'm sorry.
I forgot the filter was on.
Whoops!
Dude, someone said last time I should do a whole stream with that voice on.
I think that could be hella funny.
And then I'm gonna sound really wise as well at the same time, you know?
Try to spout armchair philosophy while playing.
Make it sound like everything I say is profound and important, you know?
I think that could be fun.
The reverberating screams of realization from leaving behind an eternal heart.
Man, that's a pain when you do that.
That sits right in the center of the tummy, you know?
That's where the pain originates.
And it spreads out to all the vital organs.
And you die a slow death.
And in Landsama, a schtickungstod.
I was just watching your season 2 of Minecraft for the second time.
Perfect time for your stream.
Okay, but you cannot skip the machine.
The machine is required watching at 0.5 speed.
I'd like some schtickungstod.
I have that from some, I think it was Klamka Russell.
I think one of the songs.
The guy's talking about being inside a bathroom, you know, because he's getting the shakes because he's addicted.
And he's trying to take a shit, but then people are outside his stall, you know, banging on the door.
And they won't go away, and he's just sitting there crying.
Something like that, but in German.
By the way, thank you, Oliver, for letting us know about Limmy.
No worries.
He's one of my favorite comedians of all time.
I gladly spread the gospel of Limmy.
Far and wide.
If this was the Middle Ages, I would be a priest, you know, walking around from town to town, singing his praises.
A kilogram of steel.
What's heavier?
I wish I could do that accent, man.
I think it's so fun.
Start the gameplay.
I'm so excited.
I will.
Today, I'm not going to let any of you decide what I'm going to do.
I have my own plans.
I am vetoing all the polls today.
That's right.
And I have decided we're going to do or redo the solar system.
I just wasn't happy with the way I did it last time.
I got to do it again.
You guys love the solar system?
I would hate to break this music off because it's so frickin' good.
But it is what it is.
That track was, unironically, one of the best tracks in gaming I've ever heard.
Okay.
Oh, also, I activated mouse control in the game.
I'm going to be experimenting with that.
Just to see how it is.
Apparently, it's good with some items and not good with others.
But you can still use the keyboard so, you know, I can hot swap back and forth.
So we'll see how that feels.
All right.
Let's do this.
Oh, look at this.
Funny thing is, though, I can't click on anything.
That's kind of weird.
Like, I can click, but it's not doing anything.
Maybe that's why it's hidden in config files.
New run.
Oh, actually, no, no.
Solar system.
No, no, I'm kidding.
We're not going to do solar system, but we are going to do challenges.
I'm really sad about 8 and 11.
I kind of want to do those first.
Also, I got to sneeze here, right?
Oh, my God.
Man, I should have used the nasal spray.
I may do that soon.
We're just going to skip over to this one, then.
Look at the UI here.
When life gives you lemons.
We're going to do greed as well today.
We're going to do speed runs.
We're going to do normal non- just runs, I guess you call them.
Actually, if speed runs are the fast ones, I guess walks should be the normal speed, right?
Anyway, let's see.
Lemon mishap.
Create a small pool of damaging yellow creep that lasts for the room.
And then we have lemon party.
Habits.
Do we have a lemon habit?
Recharges one bar of I6 active item each time he takes damage.
Okay, and nine bolts automatically restores one charge after active item use.
Items with a one room recharge become an automatic time to recharge.
Holy charges I6 active item on pickup.
Also, why do we look like a nun?
Like, what is this challenge?
I don't understand.
Oh, we don't have a key.
So obviously, we don't have any obligation to go fast because it's a challenge.
So we're just going to not do that.
We're going to go slow and calculated.
Oh, look at that, the boss is here.
I started with a bomb.
Oh, I thought for a second, I thought this was one of those stone chests.
Ooh, you can probably use that item that removes...
Ooh, look at this.
Wow.
Rainbows.
I forgot what I was saying.
I can get in here.
Thank you.
Also, no treasure rooms, right?
Because challenge.
Can I actually try this?
Wait.
Damaging creep lasts for the... Okay, actually, may not be too bad.
Sup, nerds?
Yo, lemon party?
It's kind of good.
What?
Did you see the damage?
I like that.
I am surprised.
I thought it would be like a little tickling, but it's actually solid damage.
Right here, guys.
Yeah!
Who's the man?
Or the nun, I guess.
Should I blow this guy up?
So if I blow this guy up, I am actually gonna get something.
Hold on.
Also, I need to stop that.
Where's my freaking window?
There it is.
What did I write?
Observations...
Let's see here...
Secret room devil chance.
Oh, attacking random enemy...
Yeah.
We're gonna get devil chance from this.
Oh, it's so funny.
Should I be... Oh, let me try this.
Oh, that's weird, though.
I already forgot that I had the mouse thing on.
I was just running around with my keyboard for a second.
Maybe I'll try this for a bit, just to see how that feels, but we're gonna blow this guy up.
Okay, well, we didn't get any demon chance, so maybe it's just random.
Wait!
Tinted rock!
What did I just get?
I got a shit ton of money!
I'm rich?
Wow!
I can't... Okay, I'm not gonna use the mouse.
This is so weird.
I'm gonna use the mouse if I find an item that... or where it makes sense, right?
One additional item will appear in definitely that one.
And then I'm good.
Maybe a... bomb?
No.
I'm happy.
I'm happy!
We still need a key, though.
Oh, shit.
What else?
Maybe the boss drops a key?
Oh, wait.
Did we just get a special heart?
I think we have a special heart.
Uh-oh.
We need this guy to step in the lemon.
Ah, that's not a lot of damage.
We got a tinted rock in here.
Fuck!
Misplaced it!
The plan was to push it, okay?
I fucked it up.
The plan was there, the execution wasn't.
God damn it, man.
We can't take damage.
This guy doesn't care about lemons.
This is gonna be a slow one.
Slowly but calculated.
I mean, it's working.
He tried to cut me off, that bastard!
Yeah!
That's what I call patient and solid play.
We got bombs, baby!
Blow it up!
Amazing.
Now we just need a key.
Can we potentially get a key here?
What if I destroy some pots?
Okay, well, there's money.
Not the worst thing.
I'm gonna do one more.
Rich!
But what about the key, though?
Where's my key?
Maybe in here.
Wait, wait, wait.
Could I buy a key in the shop?
Maybe.
Oh, you gotta be kidding me.
Fine.
Maybe there's more tinted rocks?
I don't think so.
Almost the perfect first floor.
I wouldn't say this is, like, amazing.
But, you know, it's definitely up there.
If I had gotten the chest there, then it was amazing.
Cheers.
Arcade?
Hmm, I could do that.
Ah, no, go in here.
Pills!
Ah-ha!
Is it all gonna be leaven party?
That's awesome!
I could donate some HP.
Uh, nah.
I'll be back, maybe.
That's...
Oh, wait, there flies.
Shh, they don't care about lemons.
They don't care at all.
There's, like, those lemons-stealing whores.
No!
That's fine.
I overreacted.
It happens.
Oh!
I thought you died!
Wow!
I just love seeing all these flies when it's lemon party, you know?
I didn't invite these guys to my party.
Before it's so good, I gotta find a shop.
Uh, there you go, guys.
Step on my piss.
Oh, that's funny.
Thank you.
Beat the titansy of the piss-masa.
And we're done here.
Boink!
The party is real!
It's pretty much guaranteed lemon party in every room.
I don't like what I'm seeing in here.
What is that?
Duplicate each blue spider and fly Isaac currently has.
Destroys all pickups on the ground in the current room when picked up.
And grants one blue spider or fly for each one destroyed.
That's horrible!
The ladder.
I mean...
I gotta...
No, we're doing lemon party.
I can't, not lemon party.
Oh!
Okay.
For some reason, I thought all the pills were gonna be lemon party.
Very underwhelming.
No other secret room, huh?
Fine.
Not the fly, man!
Lemons are useless!
It's gonna take a while.
Whoa.
He was just chilling there.
Nice!
Patch it, boy!
More money for moi.
I think I wanna keep that.
Abaddon!
Oh wait, we gotta destroy this.
I don't wanna accidentally take damage here.
And then I can think.
Okay, so we have this one.
That's kinda meh.
Whore of Babylon!
Could be good, actually.
It's only one heart as well.
Now, this one obviously is a lot of damage.
We get two black hearts.
This is complete fire.
Like, I need that.
That's two blue and one red.
With this one, two red, two blue.
Hmm...
I think...
We're gonna play it conservative.
I take this, and I don't take...
What?
Oh!
Oh no!
Well, fuck.
May as well take this now.
God damn it, man!
Ohhhh...
I gotta play perfect now, otherwise it's over.
This is just like a sasil now, except we don't fly and we aren't kick ass, you know?
We're just a little shitter.
At least I have lemons.
And my damage is...
Oh!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Yeah, see, that's what we need now.
That's good.
Lemon!
Stay mad.
Lemons!
For everyone!
I'm gonna make my own little lemon island.
Nice.
It's actually not that bad.
This is pretty okay.
Oh my God!
Kill him!
My aim is terrible.
This guy has the same dodge!
Wow!
Impressive.
They can't reach me.
Step into my piss.
Oh, wait, why did that open?
Oh, blue hearts!
Dude, I think we confirmed it.
At this point, I'm gonna save my key actually.
We're saving it for a shop or something.
Nice.
Damn.
Oh, wait, oh, oh, oh.
Wow.
Wait, I could just lemon party these guys.
Why didn't I do that?
Okay, what have we got?
BFF.
Doubles the damage of familiars.
Could be good.
If I had some, but I don't.
Why is this item perpetually question marked?
I have picked this item up at least three times.
I don't, it's a bug.
It's a bug.
I'm gonna take this though.
And that.
Oh, keys is actually what I needed, that's great.
I will buy the BFF, I think.
Just in case I get followers.
We also have one bomb I can buy, but no, we have seven.
Should be okay there.
Step into my office!
Come here.
Clean so far.
Alright!
Peep!
We're gonna be peeing on him.
He also pees.
He was born in it, he was molded by it.
He's not fazed.
I'm trying to do this, I feel like this run so far has been almost perfect.
Like I've been playing so well.
Shit.
Dude,
these little bastards are annoying.
Nice!
Okay guys, I really gotta, I gotta go use my nasal spray, because I'm losing my mind.
As soon as I start streaming, my nose starts acting up.
I'll be back in like a little bit.
Okay, here we are.
Also, I just see, I see the tinted rock now.
We got a lock, a health, and a heal.
We should still be transformed though, right?
Even with this, so that's good.
Ha, more bombs, sure.
Uh, I could go back and do the, the curse.
I think I'm gonna do it.
Wait, are we, did we just lose the thing?
Ranch damage and speed up went at half a red heart, okay.
So let's find a...
machine.
A donation machine, blood donation.
There may not be any actually.
Okay.
Weird room.
Let's look for secrets.
I think, oh, it's not here because there's water there.
Uh, probably here.
Down here.
How am I like so good today with that?
We got 10 bombs, I'm definitely, ha ha, destroying mushrooms.
Come on.
Be good to me.
All right.
Let's see.
That's really painful.
That's a really bad debuff.
Yikes.
That was really bad.
We got to find some more tears.
That's okay.
That's the chance you take when you gamble, right?
You got to be ready to accept the consequences when things don't go your way.
Lemon!
Go in the corner so I can blow you up.
Let's not go in there just yet.
Come on.
I just killed this guy.
I can afford that.
It's a little steep, but I'll take it.
Ooh, flight!
That's huge.
Right in the center of things.
This is my phase of operations.
Okay, good.
Look how patient I'm playing, man.
You've never seen this kind of patience before.
Tactical, precise, calculated.
I want to go in here.
Lemon for you.
Goddamn, man.
We lost the whole heart there.
On that maneuver.
Okay, just keep going this way.
Let's not forget we can fly if we need to.
I could have used my lemon party there and they would have calmed down on this.
I'm going.
Gurdi.
Lemon.
Oh, you son of a gun.
Stay in my piss.
That's it.
Love that.
Speed and range, okay.
I'm not done on this floor.
See, I could go grab this key, but is it really worth it to sacrifice a flight for that?
I think not.
We need more.
Watch this.
Three for three, baby.
Three for three.
I feel like I figured out the secret room.
A chance to gain one additional cent each time you pick up a coin.
And my current one...
spawns a blue fly when picking up coins.
I want this.
And I'm going to blow these fools up, too.
Steamsail!
Well, well, well.
That's very nice.
I really need to find a donation machine.
Maybe there's one in there, actually.
I'm even going to do it twice.
In fact, we can do it multiple times, because we got some hearts lying around.
Ultimate, optimized gameplay coming up.
I do apologize, but...
This is fun, man.
I like optimizing like this, okay?
Don't hate the player, hate the game.
Look at
all this money I'm getting.
Oh, yeah, I'm taking this heart, too.
Oh, baby, yeah.
So what is happening with my...
Oh, it's because I'm healing up and then I...
Yeah, I understand.
Thank you.
How about a tenor?
Could I get that?
Look how rich I've gotten off of that machine so far.
I'm going to grab this half-heart.
Where are you?
There you are.
And this one as well.
I can't grab that, but there's one more.
We can do one more.
This one up here.
And I guess I could also walk into this room.
Let's do it.
Fuck it.
See, what is that bullshit?
That's the thing that...
Oh, actually, wait.
Hold on, that's actually good for me.
Stabbed Isaac at the start of each floor, depleting as many red hearts as it can without killing him.
The stab grants bonus damage and speed.
The more health sacrifices this affects, the more stats it will provide.
Well, well, well.
That's totally good for me.
Actually insane.
And instead of going back and...
Yeah, we're just going to go now.
Because it's going to remove my health, right?
Actually, we're not done on this floor.
Uh, Lemon?
Jesus.
This room is chaotic.
How the hell am I going to do this?
Puberty.
This room sucks!
Slowly but surely.
Yeah!
Finally, it's this guy's turn to die.
Okay.
Whoa.
What?
Ho!
Shit.
Shot speed?
No!
I've been getting a little unlucky with these pills here.
I'm going to have to be honest.
I really have been.
See, should I fly here or not?
No, I have six bombs.
Uh, hmm.
Can I walk past without?
Probably not.
I should have gone into the shop first.
Lemon!
That better be some good stuff in here.
Wait, is that the second shop?
No, it's not.
Oh, the steam sale is going to go wild.
Uh, except there's nothing I want.
Oh, this sucks ass, man.
That's a blue fly.
I mean, I can buy this just to get the one out of three on Beelzebub.
Right?
That wouldn't be a bad strategy.
Maximum of 20 flies.
Sure.
I'll do that.
I think I'll take a, uh, this one.
Okay.
What an underwhelming shop.
Okay, uh, I got this.
Hold on.
Yes!
I mean, actually, that's a bit of extra money.
That's right, I'm penny pinching!
Sue me.
That's what happens to patient people.
That right there is efficiency.
So, actually, I probably should do this again here, because...
No, no, no, I'm going to gain a damage up for the more hearts I lose, right, with the stabbing motion.
So, uh, maybe I'll give this guy some coins.
See what we get.
Yo!
Okay, that's good.
Also, we're at 2-lock right now.
If it matters.
2-lock is good.
Dude, so far, this is... really good.
I'm rich!
Uh, no!
No!
Man!
Chance of finding a card as a room clear reward.
I have to add an additional card to chests.
Nah, not feeling that one.
Dude, am I just...
Holy shit, man.
Oh!
I am earning so much money in this casino.
Is this the best casino of all time?
What happened?
Let's not spend all the money, though.
We're going to stop at some point.
Wow.
Dude, having lock definitely helps in the arcade.
I think that's confirmed.
A pill.
Puberty!
We need one more.
And then good things happen.
Uh, yep.
I'm scared of going to the blood donation.
Is that going to take away my eternal heart?
Let's try.
We're testing.
It's not!
Okay, great.
That makes me happy.
Good to know.
Wow.
Dude, I love gambling.
More pills!
Lemon party, and we get this one.
Infinite gambling.
I don't even want to leave this floor!
Guys, I'm going to set up tents.
This will be my base of operations.
I will never leave.
I mean,
I'm just waiting for the game to, you know, blow up one of these machines or something, but so far, it's just not happening.
Oh!
Okay, good to get that out of the way, though.
That's actually really valuable to find that.
Yeah.
I wa- Yes!
Uh, no, I don't want that.
Actually, yes.
May as well do it.
Just to get it out of the room.
It's- Oh!
Yeah!
I'm a winner!
Nice!
Keep donating!
I'm telling you, gambling is broken.
Financing my gambling!
What's this?
Lock up!
More luck!
We're never going to end!
A blackie!
In my ba- What?
What?
No, give me that!
I'll see you later, that was a great room!
Fantastic, bro!
Now we move on.
Oh wait, now we have a blue heart, so now this opens!
We need a full blue heart.
I don't have that.
That's okay.
Uh, have we found a secret?
We have found a secret.
Let's go!
Best floor ever.
Curse of the unknown.
Okay, whatever.
100% demon mode.
I have at least more than one row of hearts, and the last one is a half blue.
We are transformed.
Dude, our damage is despicable!
Shot speed is also in the gutter.
Why did I pick up those monies?
Walk into my piss!
Dude, they're trying to cut me off!
I meant...
As well as it's going right now, the damage situation is despicable.
Shot speed, tears, damage, it's all in the gutter.
Okay, damage is actually fine, but the rest, you know?
Uh, go here.
I'm gonna blow this up.
Okay.
Too bad.
We could maybe step...
No need to pick up that money, because we are full.
Show me the shop, though.
What a room!
Wait, this guy's flying or what?
Is he floating?
Yeah, he's not being affected by the pea.
These guys are, though.
Come at me.
Oh, this is just horrible, man.
Save me from this torment.
Uh,
you know what?
Why not?
It's the blokes.
Yeah, that's right, step into that piss.
You know you want it.
Oh, what is that color?
Oh, we got him!
Nice.
He died fat.
I guess he was standing in the piss.
That's what's happening here.
Oh, I hate this item so much.
It's so bad.
Uh, doubles coins!
Sure.
Doubles keys?
I mean, that one could be pretty... Is that... Wait, spades?
Yeah, keys.
Okay, sure.
Two red hearts?
Ooh, that means we can go step... No, we cannot go step.
Because we have a bunch of black hearts.
Just spawn them, I guess.
You can double coins, grant flight, and...
I'll take that, I guess.
What do we have?
Guppy's collar and...
The mark.
Plus one black heart.
That's gonna take us to two out of three on Leviathan.
Which could be pretty good.
Uh, what's in here?
Yikes.
Uh, I have exactly two red hearts.
I could take both.
That's not bad.
I think I'm taking both.
Yep.
It is what it is.
Now we go back.
Oh, the speed though.
Wait, did I just gain a bunch of speed from that item, or...?
Point two is not that much.
Feels like way more.
But I guess it's because we transformed, or...
It's got a B.
Why am I doing this?
I know why I'm doing this.
There's a secret room here.
No, there's not.
Maybe here.
Aw, man.
Too bad.
I let him pull me in there.
Shit.
More coins.
Where's the shop at?
Okay, then.
I don't need more money!
Wow.
Come on.
My shots are so slow to get at him.
He's outrunning them.
Okay, come on, please be good here.
That one for sure.
I don't need more coins.
Spawns red heart pickups, but I don't have any red hearts right now.
I guess I may as well do it.
I mean...
Why the fuck not?
Uh...
No, I...
I like this more.
I'll take a bomb, I guess.
God, it feels bad having all this money and not having anything to spend it on.
Horrible feeling.
Stop with the money!
Give me pills.
Yes!
No.
I'm not gonna use my last.
There are limits.
Okay.
We're not done exploring, though.
Ew.
Stand in my piss!
Dude, it's actually so good.
Wow.
Drive-by.
That was the only way to... Oh, nice!
Eternal hardy!
For Marty.
I'm just gonna take it now.
It's gonna be okay.
Any tinted rocks for daddy?
Not that I can see.
Oi!
Phew.
That make... Yeah, that's that.
We're done here.
Moving on.
We could... Nah, I'm not gonna do it.
Okay, so I think I'm gonna grab this and take that with me.
Uh, first we do this, though.
Two of diamonds.
Just for the lulz.
And it's time for mom.
I think we're pretty prepared here.
Oh!
I hate the sound effect on that.
It's terrible.
Follow me.
Oh, wow.
I'm kinda throwing right now.
Oh, they're flying.
I need shot speed, man, and I need it now.
Yikes.
I stepped on the...
I may actually just die.
This may be the end of the run here.
Game is too hard, man.
Hoi!
Like, it is legitimately difficult to play when you have this little shot speed.
What's that?
Lazy worm plus damage?
Less shot speed!
Okay, well...
I'm in trouble.
This guy's a king.
I can't kill him.
Ha ha ha!
Hey!
It's over.
The run is over.
I can't kill anyone.
Somehow, this run was so good, but it was so terrible.
I don't know what's going on with my tier situation, man.
Uh, oh, I mean, sure.
We don't need money anymore, so why the heck not?
I think I'm just gonna go for it.
Wish me luck.
This is gonna be a tough one.
A real tough one.
Okay, okay.
Lemon.
Spread the entire floor in lemon.
Hoi, yoi, yoi.
Whoa.
Okay, okay.
The lemon is really helping.
Shit.
Mom!
I can't win.
I don't even have frickin' bombs to destroy these fires.
Shit.
I got one bomb.
Like, what is, like, I feel like in this game, you either are broke as shit, or you are the richest man that has ever lived.
There is no in-between.
It is crazy, man.
Rich get richer.
Confirmed by Isaac.
I don't know, man.
We gotta...
We gotta find something.
Okay, well, a bunch of bombs can help, actually.
Also, I should be using the hanged man.
Just in case of creeper, you know?
Not that there's a lot of it, but anything's gonna help.
Like, the speed at which these guys charge is otherworldly.
I know you want to jump to me.
Yeah.
What the...
Oh, no.
Guys, I think we're done.
We need some lemon up in this.
That lemon did a lot.
Get lemon, nerd!
Lemon party saves the day.
Guys, gambling shall save us!
Come on!
Kill me!
Health me!
I'm telling you, there's no in-between!
It's a fucking joke, man!
Uh... sure.
Yeah!
We can't lose.
We cannot lose to this.
Yeah, get out of there.
You like this?
Ah...
Two...
Lemon!
Oh, yes.
How about I...
Yes!
Oh, man.
Oh no, we're not done.
Walk into my piss!
What the fuck?
Come on!
Wow, my heart rate.
All right.
Two hearts.
We can do it.
We can maybe go step, actually.
With all this healing.
Uh... definitely doing this.
Yes!
Okay, we got it, we got it, we got it.
We got it.
Let's go!
Let's put one in the center.
Then we're going to try and put one on each of these corners thingies.
You know what I mean.
That's for you!
Yeah.
Lemon!
Lemon, lemon, lemon!
Potty!
Wait, the lemon potty's not affecting the outer limbs.
Why is mom not stepping into the lemon?
Not affecting her.
Good.
That's for you!
I was predicting that she would spawn there, I was wrong.
No more bombs.
We got lemon, though.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Come on, come on.
Fucking asshole.
Yes!
That was so fucking close.
Wow.
There we are.
What a first round, huh?
What a warm-up.
Holy shit.
Okay.
Let's do some random.
Let's do a greed random.
Just to switch it up a bit.
Win streak one, by the way.
Let's not forget.
Okay.
Yum heart, and we go down here, of course.
Man, I forgot how slow this character is.
Ooh, that's a good start.
I would say that's a very good start.
I don't even want to see what's up there yet, I just want to start.
And we have to remember, halfway through, it's time to save money.
Oh god.
This is gonna get crowded real fast.
I mean...
Dude, calm down!
How the hell?
This character sucks, man.
Like, at least the start is horrible.
You have no damage output.
I'm gonna lose right now, right here.
Look at all this shit on my screen!
Anything that's not a sasil is just bad!
This balance, though, is so well tuned.
Jesus fucking Christ.
Holy shit.
I need to smoke after that.
I don't even know what I want here.
Uh...
I mean, this is kind of good, I guess.
I'm gonna see the secret rooms, right?
Uh...
I'll take that, and I'll take this.
Gotta get that healing.
We gotta get one bomb and one key.
Oh my god, please die.
One of them has gotta be close, right?
Yeah, okay, there we go.
I think the other one is very low.
Ah, shit, that was so bad.
My damage is 2.7, it feels like I have 0.1 damage right now.
Why does it feel so bad?
I don't understand.
This is like...
Not that bad damage, stat-wise, I don't understand.
Yeah, get caught in a loop.
I like this.
Good.
Okay, now I think we buy a key and...
Oh, we can't even buy a bomb, that's so sad.
It's better be good.
Conehead, what was that again?
A soulheart and 20% chance to negate damage.
That is good.
But it's not damage, which is what I need right now.
I gotta buy this.
I need to.
That was close.
Solid, good start.
Demon.
Demon of the night.
Monster manual.
That's bad for me.
On this character, this item is pretty much shit.
Because you want to be having a lot of healing, right, and hearts and all that.
Monster manual is also an active, which is kind of sad.
But it lasts for the rest of the floor.
Which is pretty good, because there's only one floor.
Well, what I mean is...
Hmm, nevermind.
Nah.
I'd rather be able to heal.
Yeah.
I'll take this.
Let's go.
That was an incredibly difficult first floor.
Like, I was fighting and hanging on to dear life.
I'm not sure how we can do this.
We need some miracles to come in here and help us out.
I mean, cool, but...
Okay, this could be interesting.
You know what?
That could be okay, maybe.
It's a little bit of extra damage output, right?
And we have a bomb so we can get in here now.
And we can... Oh, the ultimate double whammy here.
And we get two bombs, holy shit.
Massive.
I am excited now.
Sharp key.
Five keys is actually no joke.
That's so valuable.
Placenta could be good as well.
Yeah, a lot of healing.
Another blue heart, of course.
Kind of want to bomb this.
Okay!
Not bad.
Oh yeah, right, we have these tiers now.
Let's try and get used to that.
Wait, maybe the mouse is easier.
No, definitely not.
No mouse on that one.
Wait, why is that... Oh, we're excited!
This could actually be bad.
This way, whoops.
This is going to be interesting, isn't it?
That was a bad heal.
Or was it?
I don't know.
We're saving up energy, you know, for nothing.
We're just going to sit back here and shoot and hope for the best.
We also have spectral tiers, right?
Oh, I thought I was hidden behind that mushroom.
Oh, this is chaos.
But it's not that bad, actually.
Definitely could be worse.
Good amount of money.
We can get in here.
What is that?
Anti-gravity?
Cheers will hover in place while pressing attack button.
Leasing attack button will shoot all hovering.
I mean, it does give me more tiers.
One extra tier.
This could actually be what we need, just to have that extra damage.
Oh, that's a fun one!
Look at that!
That means this trinket is shit now.
We don't want that anymore.
That's way better.
No trinket anymore.
Sharp key, I think that's good.
Just for the five keys.
BFF depends what we're going to find later, right?
Let's just hold off for now.
Come back.
Run into my tiers, nerds.
Dude, they're so fast!
Wow!
Oh, heal, right.
Can't forget that.
I mean, this is going okay.
This guy's not that scary.
Could also save my money for the next job, I guess.
BFF could come in handy if I find a familiar.
And think about it.
We're pretty much like a tank with this character, right?
So having familiars that deal a lot of damage could be really good, right?
Like, I just walk around and be tanky and my familiars are going to do all the work while I just absorb damage.
I like the idea behind that.
So I'm taking it.
And then we have...
The battery allows active items to store up to two charges.
Ha!
Yeah, why not?
I really want that!
Can we get more money?
Let's see if we can get more money.
Hold on, I gotta sit up straight here now.
Ow!
I'm just hiding behind this mushroom.
The damage situation is not great, though.
Uh, what was that I heard?
Oh, okay.
Guppy's head!
And... a lump of coal.
I think this could be good.
The other one, not so much.
Bombs are nice.
Wait, look at the hand on the floor, it's vibrating!
Weird.
Uh, I'm gonna go in here.
Woah!
Hello!
School pa- yo!
What now?
Nemimic?
Le- Le- Huh?
Plus zero soul hearts?
I remember this.
What the f- I'm not gonna pretend to understand what's happening.
This- woah.
Uh...
My tears have become brown.
And there's lights on them.
Did you see that?
I think there's a light on that tear.
What is going on here?
Let me try this now.
Haha!
I don't- hmm.
I don't know if I like that.
I'm gonna leave this behind still.
This is still not good.
Uh...
Okay, I mean, yeah.
Why not?
Ah!
Yes!
Show me the good stuff!
No, Scoblin.
Oh, that's much better.
Keys and money?
Oh, yeah.
Now I'm actually thinking.
So hold on.
With this thing.
Ten percent chance to fire a booger that sticks to enemies for ten seconds.
Damaged for a second.
Time for the booger to be homing.
If we do, uh, this thing in here.
And we- oh wait, it doesn't- oh right.
Nevermind, nevermind.
I thought I could stack those for some reason, but nah.
Wow!
Oh, nice!
Oh, this is amazing.
Oh, look, we also got this.
Wow!
I mean...
You know what, I can forgive the no damage part now.
Everything else is good.
Now we just need that damage.
And I'm happy, you know.
Uh, let's go down here.
You know what?
Let me go up here first.
In case there's this item that makes me choose in there, you know?
But there's not.
What was the effect of most cars?
Okay, yeah, whatever.
Let's go.
Uh, speed and shot speed.
Speed is good for me.
These tiers, though, are a mystery for me right now.
Especially the little light that's attached to one of them.
I'm not sure what that's about.
Oh, this thing.
It replaces tiers with an arcing explosive poison shot.
I think I gotta go for it, guys.
Now the question is...
Are there any unforeseen effects with this?
Are we good?
That was a booger.
I don't think there's any unforeseen effects.
Oh, that one was a bit risky.
Yeah, I don't know what's going on with that one.
Oh, it's every time I enter a room, then something happens.
The secret room is down here, by the way, but we can't enter yet.
We got eight coins.
I could get in there.
Why does it look like that?
That looks weird.
Oh, shit.
Oh, wait.
Dude, will that actually open a door down where all the doors are?
This is the door game mode.
Right?
This is it?
Oh, I have to remember I have bombs.
Oh, I can also donate to a refresh.
Hold on.
I'm not ready.
I'm ready.
Let's go.
Wait, are we getting cards on kills or something?
What's that?
I spawned an eye!
Is that my eye?
It hurts me.
Oh, shit.
Uh-oh.
I don't know if I like this.
That was not the idea.
But here we are.
Oh, my goodness.
Can we kill this guy?
Bye-bye-bye.
Imagine someone turns into the stream, has never seen Isaac gameplay before, and they look at this and they go, what the fuck is this shit?
That's what I would think.
Like, what is this even right now?
Wait, am I immune to bombs?
Oh, my God!
I don't take damage from bombs!
Yo!
Wait, do I?
Uh, randomly, I do.
Not all the time.
Sometimes.
I got Jaira.
Um, Remind.
Dude, I could also datamine.
Ooh.
Mmm.
Wait, that was the effect of most cards.
Nah, I'm gonna, I'm gonna...
Gift.
Ooh!
Yo!
We take this?
Uh, the question is do I- I guess I want it here, right?
Sure.
Why not?
Uh, and then we have a bar of soap.
That's not gonna help me.
What I need right now is survival.
That's all I need.
So let's go reroll again.
Mom's heals is range.
That was the effects of most act- Do I- Can I double the datamining?
We gotta try.
Me too?
Happy Hail to Tit!
Alright, dude.
Wait, what?
What if I use Jaira here now?
Let's blow up these fools.
Oh wait, I know why I'm not taking damage sometimes.
It's Conehead.
It's gotta be, right?
Of course.
Okay, that bomb was going a little crazy there.
I can't trust these arcs.
Oh wait, I can charge them up as well, still, look!
I feel like my damage is kinda bad.
Not that!
Get in.
How does that work?
With my current setup, though?
Uh, wait, do I wanna do that?
Uh, we gotta try it, man.
Huh?
Oh no.
That's horrible.
Oh shit.
This may have been a mistake.
I don't think this is good.
This may actually be bad.
Hold on, we gotta go in here, though.
What do you want, son?
I don't like the delay!
Delay is bad.
Wait, wait, it's...
Hold on a minute.
It's bombing at the end!
Okay, hold on, maybe it is good.
We can go three out of three on FunGuy?
What does that do again, FunGuy?
I don't know.
Grants tears up at a slight speed down, but causes the screen and sound to become slightly distorted.
This affects stacks with multiple activations, granting more stats and making everything increasingly distorted.
I mean, everything is already distorted, okay?
Doring a room removes one stack of this item's activation effect.
I think I will transition into the mushroom.
That's right.
We're doing it.
We'll go in full crazy mode.
I need to see what my damage actually looks like, because I can't trust the numbers on my screen.
I just can't.
What was that?
Oh, a heart.
I mean, that's pretty...
Watch this.
I'm going to blow up the secret room back there now.
Hahaha!
That's awesome!
Thanks.
I didn't mean to do that, but okay.
Ew!
That's horrible.
It is what it is.
Dr. Fetus!
Wait.
How is that going to stack with my setup?
Oh my god.
Daddy long legs.
Wait, we have BFF, right?
Yeah?
He should be doing good damage now.
Sure.
Mushroom time!
Oh, nice.
Wait, why is everything just dying?
Oh, it's the daddy long legs doing his thing.
Uh-oh.
Yeah, I don't know what's happening.
Things are just dying somehow, and I'm not sure why.
Oh, all these eyes, though, are going to maybe become a problem?
Hahaha!
Disco!
I have pretty good damage, guys!
This damage is solid!
I don't understand it, but...
Oh, I didn't mean to parse that.
Fuck.
Okay, here we go.
I didn't mean to!
That was a mistake!
They're doing a lot of damage to me.
What's that?
Seven seals, grands is a wondering harbinger.
He's going to be really strong, though, BFF!
I'm taking it!
This may have been a huge mistake.
What we need now, guys, is survival.
We need this, is what I'm saying here.
That's what we need.
That's not what we need, so we're going to have to go ahead and reroll.
Again, again, again...
Nice!
No!
Oh, we're poor.
Oh!
I bet.
I think we're done on this floor.
Not much else to do.
I can take this, but...
Yeah.
I'm good.
Let's keep moving.
Also, we've got to start saving money soon.
I don't know when, but soon.
I should get in there.
Oh, batteries!
I'm going to destroy all this, in case there's another one of those secret rooms.
Or not secret rooms, but downstairs places.
Here we go.
I also still have the data miner.
Not sure if I want to use it.
It kind of scares me a little bit.
But I think I should.
We should use it.
We don't care about this.
Let me data mine this bastard.
Huh?
Why am I here?
That's weird.
A pill.
Well, there we go.
Good pill.
Load these two up as well.
Oh, we don't need to use bombs here.
Uh, let's not go in there yet.
Uh, bombs, X-10, what is that?
10 bombs.
It's exactly what it says.
Wow, that's... okay.
I really thought there would be more to that.
Okay.
Oh, that is a friend.
I thought he was mine.
Ah, I don't want that.
PJs!
He has all red hearts.
Holy shit!
We're going to come back here when we're low HP.
That... whoa.
Oh, don't go down there.
Don't go down there.
Not yet.
He's going to go to the next stage.
I'm going to go in here.
Guppy's... I mean, sure, why not?
We're not going to heal yet.
We don't have a... a machine in here that can re-roll.
Oh, wait, I forgot about the secret room.
What's that?
Slowly pulls all the pickups and all...
Oh!
Now, I like my boogers.
Thank you very much.
I think I'll take this now.
Uh, we don't need that, actually.
Our damage is fine.
I'm having way too much fun with this.
Things are just dying.
Oh, that's a... oh, we're done.
Okay.
I think we start saving money now, guys.
This is the moment we save.
Yeah, just keep going.
I don't know where he is.
I don't care.
Oh, yeah, sometimes they're homing, right?
So my lasers are homing towards them.
Well, that's how you do it.
We're going to do the same thing again.
Wow, that was it, huh?
A little brimstone.
He's going to be even more strong, so yes.
Nice!
More blue hearts.
Loving these demons today.
29 coins.
Should I be buying something, let me think?
We have three... oh!
Did I get it or not?
Did I just get cheated?
Motherfucker.
Okay, well, we're in the shop.
Uh, we are not going to buy anything.
Uh, we're not going to buy anything.
We don't buy anything at all.
Wait, maybe we're buying something.
Nah, I thought it was real money.
It was just play money.
This is the strategy.
Just sit back here.
This character started off so bad, and look where we are.
This is one of the reasons this game is so addicting.
I refuse to move up.
I will stay here.
Okay, I'll go up a little bit.
Lots of money here.
Again.
I don't know what's up there, but it's dying.
It's dying.
Dude, I'm having such a blast with this shit.
What the fuck is that?
Look at that!
I'm scared!
I'm scared, man!
Are you going to shoot at me?
Are we fine?
Are we friends?
Okay, that's scary.
Um, Cube of Meat.
I could buy that, I guess.
Uh, let's go in here.
Pills, I love those.
Puberty.
Full of hell.
Hey, okay.
Not that we needed that.
It is what it is.
Blow things up.
Ew!
Is that a ham?
It's a sausage.
Whoa.
Damn!
This item, huh?
Increases chance of finding devil rooms, angel rooms, and planetariums?
Dude, the sausage is out of control.
I forgot the two coins.
It's okay.
Here we go.
Wish me luck.
Okay, I'm going to mushroom so hard.
Okay, here we go.
Mushroom time!
Oh, crap.
I don't know where this guy is.
Oh, shit.
Dude, these eyes are scaring me.
They may actually kill me.
The eyes may kill me.
We gotta kill them before the eyes kill us!
Keep mushrooming!
MUSHROOM!
What the fuck is happening in here?
Okay, then.
I may have taken too many shrooms.
I think I'm in trouble.
Dude, the eyes are killing me.
It's over!
Stay to mine!
I couldn't have done anything there.
The eyes just killed me.
The eyes, man!
The eyes!
Wow.
Well, you know what?
That was worth it, just for that.
Because that was fun as hell.
Okay.
Let's do a speedrun, man.
I feel it.
Also, how do I even...
I thought for sure the question mark here would be Delirium.
But apparently it's not.
So I don't even know.
Also, this one.
Unlock...
Wait, did I unlock a new character?
Oh, that's that guy, right.
Let's just random.
Fuck it.
Here we go.
It's her again!
Okay, we can't really speedrun with her, but you know what we can do?
Step, baby!
And what do we have right in front of us?
The step room.
Okay, no more stepping.
We're going to come back.
Stepping is kind of risky when you can't see your HP.
I just realized.
Maybe a bad idea.
Like, I physically tried to move out of the way in front of my monitor, you know?
Like, angling my head.
Just now.
I was very immersed.
Okay, give me that.
So I should be at...
I don't know how many hearts I start with, with her.
I think it's four or five.
So I'm definitely at three hearts right now.
Like, fully healed three hearts.
Wow, nothing?
Damn.
Let's see what we get.
Soy milk.
Wait.
I have 2.73.
No, wait, never mind.
I have 3.5...
I was about to say I'm going to have negative damage.
But that's not the case.
I have 3.5 damage.
Minus 2.8.
Minus tier size.
Significantly reduces knockback.
Here's what we're going to do.
I'm going to leave it for now.
If I find damage somewhere, I'm going to take it.
If not, I'm actually just going to leave it.
Because I don't like, you know, shooting little water droplets that do nothing.
This is the plan.
Heal.
Now we should be at full health.
We have one bomb.
We can use to get a key if we need to.
Oh, cupot!
What is this one over here?
Nightlight.
Yeah, I have no money.
Shit.
I feel bad.
We're going to need a miracle to afford any of that.
Oh, you know what?
The fast attack rate would actually be super good if you have boogers.
Higher chance of applying, right?
Or any type of effect that relies on luck, you know?
Because you're just brute forcing more attacks.
So if I find damage or something like that, then we can think about it.
Oh, fuck.
Wait,
as long as you attack him, he's like stun locked.
He can't spawn any more flies.
Did I read that right just now?
I feel like that's what just happened.
Tears and shot speed.
Okay.
Whoa!
Huh?
I thought this was a planetarium.
Hold on a minute.
Before I go.
I may actually pick that up.
And we also have...
Oh, I don't have any bombs though.
Shit.
Okay, fine.
I'm going to take this.
I mean, it's got to have like a net positive, right?
Since it's an item.
I mean, it is pretty fast.
Imagine having bookers with this though.
I'm going to be...
Or the one that applies bombs on impact.
Imagine that.
Wait, this is a water bucket and it's full.
This one is empty.
What does that mean?
What is this?
Downpour.
Oh, it's definitely pouring.
It's a whole new place.
Oh, that's disgusting.
Ew!
Dude, I knew I should have taken this item.
I do no damage.
Oh, it's raining and it's like thundering too.
Oh, I like this.
This is a nice atmosphere.
That took forever.
Oh, I can't get down there.
Okay, okay.
Huh?
They're reflections.
No, wait, they were invisible?
This is awkward.
Dude.
Bomb the shit out of that.
Squeezy.
I'm telling you, rich get richer.
I never find damage when I find this item.
That gives me a lot of attack speed.
Never.
We're definitely shooting fast, though.
There's no denying that.
Oh, man.
Yo, this is hella cool, man.
New enemies and shit?
Uh, yeah, I go in here.
Fuck, maybe I don't.
They're collecting rainwater in these buckets.
Yeah, yeah.
Why is this happening?
Is it because I beat Delirium?
Whoa!
My reflection!
More rain, shot speed, less lock, boomerang.
That's interesting.
Shot speed...
Yo, shot speed multiplier?
That could be interesting, actually.
This one is unknown.
No, I think I want this one.
This seems interesting.
But I can't get in!
No!
It's probably a choice.
I can't take all three, so I'm going to come back with a bomb.
I want the left one.
What are these?
Oh, look at this guy!
Ha!
Throwing buckets at me!
I don't like these little fuckers.
Oh, wait.
He's actually destroying the rocks for me.
Increase the size of Isaac's...
I mean, sure, why not.
I got nothing else.
I'm not going to waste my key there, because I don't have any money.
Depower them.
Boss is here.
We got a bomb!
Yo, this is great.
I love this level.
Great music.
Yeah, dude, that's sick.
That's really cool.
The Rainmaker.
This game never ends.
Oh, my God.
Okay, so you run around in a circle.
Cool, boss.
I like it.
Magic scab.
Uh, yeah.
Gimme damage!
Flight, though!
Damage up and speed down.
Heal contact damage while active.
Can break rocks by walking into them.
I need this.
Dude, I need this.
Absolutely, I'm taking that.
Are you kidding me?
In this economy?
You know I'm taking it.
No bombs, though?
Oh, wait, I can take this down.
Uh, oh, right!
Ah.
Well, that wasn't great.
Oh, I still need two keys to get into that room up there.
I forgot about that.
Wait, can I somehow...
What if I destroy those buckets with water?
What happens then?
Oh, man, I also have these two.
This is so sad.
I need keys.
Uh, this one didn't give any damage, though.
We're still tickling enemies.
I need Ipikak.
Downpour, too.
I like it.
I do.
Brr-brr-brr-brr-brr-brr-brr-brr-brr-brr.
Oh, this is awkward, man.
Oh, I see how it is.
Gotta shoot right above them.
Rainbow worms.
Tears cycle through different worm effects every few seconds.
That could be okay, actually, for all of my tears.
What if they get a damage-up, uh, multiplier, right?
Oh, okay, this one's bad, but you know what I mean.
If they get a damage-up multiplier, then they're gonna slap all of a sudden.
Oh, no.
I hate this.
Somehow they all died.
That was good.
That's very good.
Now you see what life has to offer?
Oh, it's the shop.
Yeah.
Why not?
Oh, I like the dripping sound.
Uh, Mr. Meee.
I could do that, I guess, but I need money first.
How dare you throw that at me?
Actually, you know what?
You can do that.
That's fine.
Can you take the one with the X on it?
The one right there.
Yeah, yeah.
That's it.
No.
Come back here!
Come back with the X, you motherfucker!
You bastard!
I can't believe it!
What a little fucker!
I don't know what's happening with my tears right now.
They have a life of their own, you know?
Dude, imagine if I had spectral tears, though.
Yeah, threading the needle.
I mean, this is just...
I'm making it rain myself here.
Uh, boss has been found.
I'm not ready.
I need to buy these items in the shop.
Okay, it's not that bad, actually.
Boss room teleport, okay.
I need a key for the treasure room, man!
Come on!
Is this it?
No, it's not it.
Wait, what?
Is that a mirror?
Wait a minute, something's happening here.
My reflection.
There's some kind of connection.
Maybe.
I kind of want to blow it up, though.
I need a bomb.
I need a bomb and I need a key, dude!
And I need it now!
Come on!
No, not that!
What's this little guy doing?
You see that?
There's a tiny guy down there.
Oh, that's so sad.
Uh...
Fuck.
What about fight room?
Oh, it's closed.
Dude, I'm so curious about all of this and I don't know what's happening.
Wormwood?
Well...
Oh, I'm gonna fuck you up.
Come on, then.
Yo!
Yeah, you ain't got nothing on me.
You don't know who you're dealing with.
You don't know who I am!
Who I am.
What?
Oh, okay, okay.
That's cool, keep doing that.
Huh?
Oh, oh!
Wow.
Fancy?
Oh, bastard.
No problem.
Stem cells.
Shot speed.
How about damage?
How about damage, man?
Wait.
Dude, I need...
I need bombs!
There's all kinds of interesting shit here.
Also, there's a hole in the wall.
Wait, challenge me?
Wait, what does that mean?
Oh, when I hold tab...
Oh, wait, my card changed his name when I hold tab.
I've never noticed that.
Look at that!
Wow.
Flottic Cape.
Okay, okay, okay.
Please, I need to find keys and shit.
Keys and bombs.
There we go.
Good start.
Oh, yeah, I have almost no knockback on my tears.
Okay, my damage is pretty good.
I mean, I just have so many shots, right?
These things better stay in the center.
Just saying.
How am I gonna get hit by every one of those shots?
That's crazy.
No tinted rocks?
No tinted rocks.
Oh, wait, I can fly!
Dude!
I forgot I can fly.
Did I miss something in here then?
I don't think I did.
Jesus!
Didn't mean to do that.
What is the Emperor?
Boss room.
Oh, God.
Don't take my battery!
I need it.
My tears started misbehaving at the worst time.
Uh, why not?
Fistula.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Wait, look.
Okay, hold on a minute.
Something's happening here.
What's with this door opening?
I think I need two bombs for that.
Let me see.
Book of Sin.
Random pickup.
The Wandering Harbinger.
Nah.
I'm gonna skip that.
I don't like those.
I'm not done here, though.
I want to find bombs so I can potentially get in that weird room.
They can't hit me here.
Aye, aye, aye, aye.
What
a mess!
I think the game has a hard-coded rule that says, if you pick up the item that gives you insane, uh, rate of fire, you will just not find any damage items.
I think I actually believe that.
Because I have seen so many instances of exactly this before.
It can't be a coincidence.
Just can't be.
Are you kidding me?
I have to remember I can fly!
I'm so not used to flying.
Huge amounts of money.
No shop to spend it in, though.
Aye.
Cricket set.
There it is!
Damage!
Wait, that's not...
Didn't that say one point something?
This one is only good if you have a lot of damage already.
This is a multiplier.
Shit.
So it's actually the worst it could have been right now.
But, you know, it's better than nothing.
A little bit of damage goes a long way when you have as many tears as I have right now.
I'm just gonna move on.
Oh, wait, we have three bombs.
Let's try.
Huh?
What?
Uh...
What is happening today?
Mines?
Dude, what the...
And...
Yes!
Health applies charm to enemy...
We like that.
Great!
Oh, but we can't...
Whoa.
I can't see a map, though.
Oh, my God.
Huh?
What is that?
Oh, they're charmed!
What's this?
What the hell is that?
I pressed something.
Okay, spiky boy.
Oh, yeah, I can fly.
Money.
This is cool.
They really ought to fix the...
when they show credits in this game, is all I'm saying here.
People might get the wrong idea.
Wow, look at that!
Huh?
Bob splatter!
Yo, that's a sick amount of damage!
I need that so bad!
Placing a bomb also creates a small pool of high-damaging creep.
Um...
Hold on.
I lost damage!
Oh, it's because there's cycles, that's why.
So I just happen to have a lot of damage, I guess.
But why am I not seeing the .5?
Wait, now the .5 is gone, look!
Oh, you know what?
The worm probably affected this item to make it display .5.
When there's actually no .5 on it.
That's weird.
Okay, I'm gonna keep this then.
Whoa.
Ouija board.
More tears!
Oh my god.
Oh, it's also damaged!
Ah, but wait, is it the fucking worm again?
It is.
I can't trust the worm!
Let me take off the worm.
Let me see what it says.
Okay, so it's just tears and spectral tears.
Uh, wait, the other one is...
I kinda wanna gamble here.
I feel like we have enough tears.
Finger, watch where you point that.
That's the one that does passive damage, right?
That's not super exciting, honestly.
That's kinda bad.
Okay.
Rotten tomato?
Chance to fire special tears that apply a bait effect.
Bait effect slows enemies and draws other nearby enemies to attack them instead of Isaac.
Chance increases with luck.
Oh, it's not a trinket, that's awesome!
Yo, this is gonna be crazy then.
Look how many red ones I'm shooting.
That's a good amount of red.
Oh, yeah!
I love this game.
A dice man?
What was that?
They love each other, look!
Ha!
Wait a sec.
Why would they do that then?
If not for, like, a secret or something.
Dude, spectral tears, man, I should have taken that.
Spectral tears are crazy.
I sit in a corner and just shoot, you know?
But I guess I randomly get spectral tears with my trinkets, so...
Hey.
Alright.
We're done here.
I may actually start looking into removing my active and replacing it.
Don't kill each other, guys!
I command you.
Another red button!
I think the way this level works, you gotta press all these red buttons before something happens and then you can proceed or whatever.
Uh, lots of mushrooms.
Bosses here.
Are we gonna get new bosses here, too?
Hornfell!
Isn't that the guy up in the observatory?
Joe, this is awesome!
Reminds me of old games.
Ha ha ha!
Oh my god, dude, calm down!
I think you're done, son.
More range.
Tear size is good for me.
That's huge!
That's really huge.
Uh, oh.
Is it like a blood sacrifice door?
Oh my god.
Joe!
Man, why is all of this unlocked at the same time?
This is crazy!
Mossel Liam?
Dude, I don't care what it's called.
I'm in.
You son of a bitch.
Wait, no.
We have buttons here now that...
Okay, I don't know what these buttons do.
Don't even care.
I'm killing them all.
Uh... Taurus.
Oh, this is the speed thingy.
Uh, when maximum speed is reached, I should gain some visibility when this is...
No.
I want this.
The wafer!
Ha ha ha ha!
That's good!
That's good, son.
That's really good.
Go kill each other, guys.
Yeah.
Eat the pills!
Oi, uh oh.
Ow.
I mean, we need to find a shop, and we need a stat.
Charm the enemies!
This is so much fun!
I love this build.
Here we go!
Oh!
Are you kidding me?
Hey, at least we can...
Yeah!
I'm gonna save... wait, should I save this?
I'm gonna save this.
Wait, does that replace my heart, though, if I... Wait, let me just...
Just in case.
What's this?
Yep, let's take it.
Uh, well, I don't have any... Oh, wait a minute.
Creates a duplicate.
No.
I don't like that.
If I think it's no familiar to duplicate, when it's one demon baby.
Nah, I'm good.
Humbling bundle.
Can't put pennies, bombs, keys, and red hearts to be doubled.
Wow.
I think I would rather have a pill.
No, this is actually pretty good.
Ah, shit.
Okay.
I'm just gonna move.
What was that?
Something just went...
I'll be back for that.
Upside down cross in here.
I can't even fly inside.
Oh, you need...
You need certain devil items to get in here.
You need this moon item and you need the upside down to enter these areas.
Oh.
Oh, never mind, wait.
Maybe not.
What did I do?
I'm just activating these for no reason.
Oh.
Oh!
Shit.
Get the hell out of there.
Curse of the tower.
Nah.
Callus?
What is that?
France immunity to... No, I'm flying, so I'm good.
It's just MT or...
Oh, okay.
Jesus.
Let's go.
Man, this guy has a lot of HP.
Wait, am I hitting him?
Oh, I'm not hitting him.
I see the problem.
Bon's a beggar.
He wants bombs.
I don't know about that.
We gotta get in here.
He's my friend in the center.
He's not gonna hurt me.
Oh, wait, wait.
Oh!
These buttons have always been bad, but...
Maybe not.
Oh!
Oh, shit!
Okay, I let them loose.
I see how that works.
Okay, we're gonna save this present for the demon room.
The Siren!
Yo, all these new bosses as well!
It's crazy.
She likes to be held down.
Oh, God.
She's gonna sit here and chill.
Oh!
Okay.
Sure.
Can these guys die, the little ones?
I don't know if they can.
Oh, whoa, whoa.
Oh, my God!
Oh, sure.
Bad place to be.
All I'm saying.
Wow, dude.
Yes!
We got her underwear!
Nice!
I'll take that.
Unfortunately, no special demon room.
That's fine.
We gotta go back and use this present.
Wait, I could have also used it in the boss room.
Maybe I wanna use it there, actually.
Yeah!
Just use it inside the room.
It's not a bad idea.
Screw!
Oh, my God!
Are you for real?!
Give me damage!
I don't know if I should move on, though, like...
I need more healing.
Give me healing.
Thank you.
Finally, you're listening.
What do we have here?
Fish shit.
Wait, what?
I'm gonna look at that in a sec.
She's multiplying.
Oh,
it's this buffer.
Now, Keith...
Let me see.
Spawns a blue attack, fly each time Isaac takes damage.
Wait, am I good without the worm?
I feel like this is already pretty good.
Wait, oh, wait, they come back, right?
Yeah, look at that.
Maybe I'll try and go without the worm for a bit.
See how that feels.
It's definitely... I feel like I have less AOE with it, but it's more consistent.
It's not bad.
It's okay.
Oh, my God.
You know what?
I really need something that blocks shots coming towards me.
That would be fantastic.
Oh, man, I have no map.
I wish to see what this looks like.
Also, I gotta go back for my active.
I just realized I couldn't use that battery on anything.
Oh, man.
Wait, where am I now?
No way.
Give me something good.
Give me damage.
That's not it.
Okay, well, that's damage.
I'm just gonna give him all my money.
Yeah, I like that one.
HP up, shots beat down.
I like that, actually.
Good exchange.
Oh, wait, that was my last bomb.
At least we're rich, again.
Should I be doing this?
Yeah.
Teleport to a random room, unknown.
Oh, sick.
Love the pills.
I don't think so, buddy.
I don't think so.
Telepills.
Gonna throw a rocket at me?
Wait, would you look at that?
I don't care about range.
Well, that's not true, but it's almost true.
Familiar that drops a coin every two rooms.
No, thanks.
Except, is it a trinket?
Oh, well, in that case, then I'll take it.
I thought it was a trinket.
This way.
I'm gonna grab this again.
Now, this pill, we don't know what it is, which makes it even more exciting.
Oh, hell yeah.
Yeah!
Massive energy.
I can re-roll this now.
Oh, yeah.
How good is that?
Uh, yeah.
We move on.
I want pills.
No bombs.
Go, go, go!
Okay, let's see here.
Uh, I'm doing good damage now, man.
Like, the attack speed is really so high that even with my low damage, it's good, you know?
The fuck is that?
Whoa!
Looks like my worst enemy.
Oh, my God, I don't like what's happening.
Range down.
No, I don't want that.
Get away from me.
Oh, God.
Oh, man.
Wow!
The heck?
Uh, I'm scared, man.
Kill each other.
Kill him.
Yeah!
And then he just died somehow.
I love turning them against each other.
Okay, I think we need to do this.
Good luck there.
Love it.
So, we got a weird portal thingy over there.
Oh, my God, please.
It's spawning enemies, I see.
Oh, there's a rock in the way.
Fucking rocks, dude.
It's in a very annoying spot, is all I'm saying.
Strategically placed, you could say.
Call me crazy.
Didn't this used to give me damage?
Now it's giving me tears.
Like, it's unreal, right?
The items are changing on me now.
Whoa.
I'm actually gonna blow these up.
Will they give me blue hearts at all, or...?
I don't think so.
Kill each other.
It was bound to happen.
Oh, my God, you're so evil.
Mom's wig.
Yes, mother!
You feel itchy?
Feels a red heart.
Firing has a chance to spawn blue spiders and increases with luck.
Why not?
You also have this knife.
How is that from Yes, Mother?
But it's like...
That's just, like, another familiar, I guess.
What?
Oh.
Wait, where did the gym sound come from?
There's no button.
Oh, compass!
That's good.
This is also good, dude.
We're taking it all.
The ladder?
Um, batter?
I think I'm just gonna keep moving.
That was nice.
Uh-oh.
They have, like, telepathic powers here.
Kill him!
Go!
Kill the king!
Holy HP.
How is that guy so tanky?
You cannot spawn things.
I deny.
This guy is actually scary.
Yeah, portal gone.
No more portals.
Uh, boss is here.
I think we go.
That's fine with me, honestly.
Sup, mom?
I think my knife just blocked a shot.
I definitely should have taken damage there, and it didn't.
I'm not entirely sure.
Oh my god.
That's new.
Whoa!
Mom!
I can do that, too.
Ah, dude.
Whoa, look at that door.
So, wait.
Uh, Polaroid?
Higher stages.
Oh, but this one gives me damage, though.
I need this.
We're taking that.
I need to go in here.
Yep.
Uh, we need something else for that.
I don't know what, though.
Do we need a key?
A key, maybe?
I'm not sure.
Moving on.
I still have, like, a growling in my right ear.
That was weird.
Rich!
But there's no more shops, though.
I didn't mean to do that.
Dang it.
Oh, yeah, we can fly.
I keep forgetting, man.
I'm not used to flying on non-Azazel.
It's just not a thing.
It doesn't compute, you know?
Good stuff.
Oh, my God.
I love this attack speed.
It is so much fun to just fly around and do this.
I gotta take damage here.
Ah, but we have the wafer, so we only lost half a heart.
Not bad.
Yes.
Let me check the... Oh, I see something.
I think.
Right here.
Never mind.
Love that one.
I'm telling you, pills are some of the best things in this game.
The more pills you eat, the better.
Because then you have a knowledge base of what pills do.
So even more pills get even more better, and it gets more better, and more better, and more better.
All the charges, Isaac's active item when entering a new boss room.
What do I currently have?
New attack, flies, time, Isaac.
Nah, you know what?
That's so underwhelming.
I want this.
Which means we're gonna be pilling on every boss.
Take my money.
Actually, I have keys too.
Thanks!
More keys.
Okay.
Is this like a chest man?
Is that his specialty?
Okay, hold on.
We gotta be careful now.
We're gonna wait a bit here.
This could be huge.
Rotten meat.
Keep giving me chests!
We also gotta open these chests with keys.
Let's not forget that.
Ew!
Come on, man.
One more.
What the...
did I take damage from?
What's happening?!
I'm taking damage!
Jera!
Why am I taking damage?
Massive.
This was a great arcade.
Love that arcade.
Arcades have been good to me today.
These guys can't die.
Tomatoes, though.
Tomatoes need to be eradicated!
That's it!
Ooh!
Wow!
This room was kind of difficult.
Kill each other.
I'm gonna make them all my friends.
There we go.
Now you're gonna go out and do great things for me.
Do it.
I can not see anything.
More bombs is good.
I smell a secret room right...
But wait, I can see forever on.
I guess this is gonna link down to that somehow?
Must be.
We have another I can see forever.
I guess I'm gonna save that.
Secret room discovered!
Holy...
Jesus.
Shot speed.
Hey, that's good, actually.
Walnut.
Being hit by an explosion has a 33% chance to destroy Trinket and small one clunky and Trinket.
Hmm.
And I currently have...
the charging mechanism.
I mean...
That's useless.
Give me that and...
I mean, maybe I can get a good Trinket.
Right?
This Trinket is kind of meh.
Maybe I use it once to get the charge on the boss and then fuck off after.
What's that?
Tears fire in a wide spiral pattern.
Grand spectral tears!
Chance for homing tears...
Dude.
No!
I mean, that is kind of dope, though.
I will say that.
This could be good.
I love the angled shot, actually.
It's not too angled either because we have so much shot speed.
A lot of bombs.
Like, call me crazy.
This thing used to give damage damage.
And now it's been converted to shot speed.
Bullshit!
Oh wait, that's a Trinket.
Wait, what?
Where did that card come from?
I'm so confused.
I'll take that instead.
Even though I probably don't need it.
Yes.
Hello, Pil.
Nice.
I wanted to check out this secret room anyway, right?
That's why I came here.
Give me more pills.
Unfortunate.
There we go, another one of these.
Oh, but I have angled shots, you don't!
I win.
Health up!
Yeah!
I mean, we are doing great on health.
We're actually at the point where we should be getting black hearts now.
Not blue, black hearts instead of red.
This is the plan.
Oh, oh, right, I can fly.
I can fly and I can see and I can do all kinds of things.
What was that one?
Now, boo.
I like this.
Stepping room is an option, but I reject the stepping room.
That's right, I reject it.
So here's the plan.
We're going to go back and grab that active powering up thingy.
Where is it?
That one.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
So we're going to get the active fully charged now when we enter.
And then we're going to go back and switch it up again.
Give me that for now.
You're going to die so hard.
Also, give me a shot speed up.
Yeah.
I have so much shot speed.
MG 42.
Damage is good, but it's not like that good, you know?
Like, it's okay.
You unlock the cute baby.
Damage is good.
I like it.
We take...
Uh, multi...
Dude, this could be really good.
Imagine we go behind this and we go brrr.
The entire room gets fucked.
That is going to slap.
Mark my words, dude.
Mark my words.
Uh, we got to go back first, though.
Sure.
I got to exchange my thingy.
We don't need this anymore now.
I need the...
I think I'm going to take this.
Because I can sit in a corner and go crazy with that.
And the one I just got...
Actually, is that better when I have the baby?
Because I kind of want to...
Yeah, you can make it work.
Just sort of walk like this.
A pattern like this, you know?
It's not bad.
Okay.
Uh, we also have this room.
I don't really need anything, so I'm good.
I
have money.
I'm successful.
I'm rich.
I'm handsome.
There's nothing I need.
Uh, we're going to go down, because deeper stages, right?
Let's do it!
She old!
She real old.
Um, we could go straight for the boss.
Which is exciting.
Or...
We kill everything.
Which is honestly something I like, too.
Now, I may actually exchange my trinkets, because I don't like the angled thingy.
I don't want to...
I'm only going to take half a damage, though, if I do this.
Heh heh, right?
Not bad.
I get to keep my black heart.
Bro!
I did not get to keep my black heart.
Unfortunately.
Is that a Reaper man?
I
can't even see the changing effect when I shoot through the multidimensional baby.
One of them is invisible, no?
I'm scared.
Yeah, I need to get rid of this trinket.
We need a new trinket.
Keep going south.
I mean, that is pretty cool when that happens like that.
Axlax.
Oh, I need to use the pill.
Okay.
Uh,
nothing in it?
What the hell?
Uh, go here.
Thank you.
Shot speed?
Dude, even more?
Shot speed up.
Shot speed up!
Gimme more pills.
Brrr!
Man, we have insane range.
Thirty-three range!
What?
That's crazy.
Oh my god!
Gimme the best of the best of the best, sir!
Jera.
Oh, there it is.
We're gonna save this Jera?
Until we have a million blue hearts.
Wait, we have minus one luck, so maybe this is bad.
Two of space, doubles...
Uh, I wonder if the Jera is gonna duplicate that as well.
Come on.
Yeah, luck is definitely affecting this machine, I can tell you that.
Okay.
Do it.
I mean, I don't even know if I need it.
Forty-four keys, ladies and gentlemen.
That's how crazy this is!
Wow!
I nearly shoot straight, even with this trinket.
Because of my shot speed.
Also, I'm super fast, all of a sudden.
We can go in here.
We cannot go in there.
Bad idea.
I need to find a trinket replacement.
Uh, what does Exlax do again?
Tunnel of Slippery Creep, okay.
Let's save that for a boss or something.
Nope, don't shoot me.
Scary.
I'm not doing too great on HP here.
Also, these eyes are gonna mess me up.
No, this is bad.
I'm stressed!
Huh?
Time has been applied.
I don't know why or how, but...
Wait, I can charm his little guys.
Oh, he did.
I don't like this.
We gotta get rid of this trinket, man.
But I need another trinket.
I don't wanna just run around with no trinket.
That's kinda sad, you know?
Sure, just keep giving me money.
Lord knows I need it.
Whoa.
Whoa!
The fuck are you?
That's a new one.
Ranged down.
Honestly, I'm kinda considering it.
Nah.
Let's not do that.
Okay, uh...
What now?
I think we just go.
It's time to go kill Satan.
We're gonna X-lax right on him.
We're gonna bomb the shit out of his legs that come down.
See if we can time this again.
Bomb.
Shit.
Okay, okay!
I
mean, my damage is pretty good.
Not bad.
Here he comes.
Here, come defeat.
Heh heh.
No problem.
And that's that.
That's all she wrote.
I think this...
Like, what's happening right now...
Is what's classifying as deeper, uh...
Oh, wait.
What did I say?
Wait a minute.
Little horn.
Oh, with my... with all my little shots?
Yo!
That's gonna be insane DPS.
Loof.
Yeah, that's bullshit.
Uh...
No, I don't care.
Hmm.
Not bad either.
These two.
Chance increases with luck.
Well...
I don't have a lot of luck, so maybe this one.
Ah, that also increases with luck.
Ah, but I shoot so many.
It should be okay.
I think this one.
This one.
I can take multiple.
Let me in.
Wait!
Is this the door?
For the full key?
Oh my god!
Look at it!
It's like a slot for it!
Oh, shit!
Heh, look at all the heads!
I'm in danger though, like...
My damage is not that good.
I think I'm... I think we're done here.
Okay, you know what?
I've had it with a fucking trinket!
Suck it!
There we go.
Fuck you.
No more.
I've had it up to here with it!
Ex-lax!
Slip on my piss!
Oh god, oh god!
What the fuck?
I need pills.
I need pills, man.
Huh?
Fire tears with Randy?
Oh, sure.
Random buddy.
Telepills?
I think that's a bit risky.
Let's do it.
Oh, yeah.
Feels good, yo.
I see your stance.
I see your stance!
Something I've noticed, these guys can only go horizontal.
So you can actually kind of abuse that somehow.
I just don't know how, but you can.
Most likely, there's a way to abuse that.
These guys are gonna do lasers?
Not if they lasered themselves!
Oh my goodness!
Holy shit!
I'm in deep danger.
Where's my healing at?
There's a severe lack of healing around these parts.
This could be healing.
It is...
huge.
Oh no, I lost it.
So many lasers just everywhere.
I need to keep it in vision.
I need to see what he's doing.
Yeah, there's the laser.
My damage is just not good enough.
Man, I'm struggling.
Shots speed up.
Sure, why not.
Oh, we're back here now.
Man, I really want to enter that door!
Wait, what?
Oh no.
This is the end, guys!
This room is too good.
Maybe.
Playing inverse, space invaders.
Oh god.
Oh shit!
Come on!
Dude, this guy's tanking.
Oi, oi, oi, healing.
That's so needed, thank you.
Man, oh man.
Of course, we're lost in here as well.
I can't see shit.
Get that away from me!
Yeah.
No.
No, no, no, no.
Those bombs away from me!
What a cute little bomb you have.
What is that?
Bombs getting big and flat?
Ah, sure.
Maybe I can use my ten bombs to kill the boss that's here.
Can I even find a boss?
Or do I need to go through that weird ass door that I can't get through?
I mean, if there's a boss here, then we can fight.
It's gotta be soon.
Because we have cleared so many rooms.
Oh god!
How did I not take damage from that?
I'm surprised.
Yes!
Telepills?
You know what, we could use it if we find a boss.
Wait.
That looked destructible for a second.
Dude, where am I?
Can I enter now?
Oh!
I never went south, that's kinda crazy.
Of course I'm getting money.
What a cruel joke.
If we find the boss room, we can teleport out of shitheads to hit the fan.
And then maybe something... happened.
Yes!
I guess I'm healing a- wait, this is dead end though.
Let's do this like a labyrinth, we're gonna keep taking right.
Paths.
Okay, there's nothing in here.
Then we go like this.
Then we go up here.
Here.
Nothing.
Like that.
Dude.
Then we go this way.
Nothing.
Like...
There's something about that spot.
I...
I am so lost.
Ah!
Here we go, here we go.
I was so afraid that I couldn't progress because I needed to go through the door or something.
Okay.
So there's nothing up here.
Turned them into my friends.
No problem.
I can see forever, but I can't.
Oh, actually, maybe I can.
Yo!
What?
For some reason I just didn't think there were any secret rooms here.
Sick.
I mean, okay.
Let's see if we can find more secret rooms.
There is more.
I wonder if enemies are close by or next to each other.
And one of them gets hit by the hand.
I wonder if that's AOE.
Bombs damage, poisons enemies.
Yeah, why not?
I guess we'll do it.
Okay.
Bunch of hearts.
Healing if I need it.
Here's the boss!
I'm going to take... Hold on, there's one heart somewhere here.
Oh, shit.
This way?
No, I thought it was like a full heart.
I didn't want to waste the two hearts.
Because my plan is this.
If things go south in the boss room, I'm going to teleport out and heal up again.
So every single heart matters here.
Somewhere, there's a full heart.
Wait, what was that?
Oh.
I don't remember where it is.
Man, I wish I had a map for this place.
Let's go down here.
I think we're just going to go in with what we have now.
Maybe one more check on the left side.
Here?
Is there a heart here?
There was one more, though, somewhere.
Okay, maybe not.
I'm imagining things.
Here we go!
Little lamb?
Some kind of demonic creature!
Okay, okay.
Kind of looks like Eve.
Like a male, disgusting version of her.
What is that even in the center there?
What is that little thing?
Oh, shit.
It's not even that hard.
I gotta be careful.
Oh, okay.
I have my hand on the telepills right now.
In case I need to.
Would you like to do a victory lap?
Uh, yes.
Golden God achieved.
You're the best.
The gate is open.
Huh?
What happened?
What the fuck is going on?
Uh, okay.
We got the key!
We're going back to the door.
This may not be the right key, though.
Lock down.
Yeah, we need the other key.
Uh, we need to step, actually.
Yeah.
Um, there's a shot.
Wait, we have 99 coins.
I don't know what's happening right now.
We're just starting over with all kinds of items.
Like a new game plus or something.
I'm not sure what's going on.
Also, everything is much faster.
Or maybe that's just me.
Like, I'm just, I don't know.
Compost?
Shit.
Right until the end.
These pills are getting expensive.
Verve?
Bro, this is a bad deal.
Bad deal.
Holy shit.
What a mice sink.
Wow.
I'll be sticking to the pills in my mom's bottle, thank you.
Damage!
Any damage right now is massive.
Gimme me.
Wow, he just got deleted.
Look at my knockback, though.
Can't even reach me, bitch.
Shot speed.
Oh, I...
Actually, yeah, I didn't want the other one anyway.
Oh!
Yes!
But wait, there's X's on the others.
What does that mean?
Maybe there's X's on everything that isn't what I'm currently doing.
Also, I'm seeing things on the map.
How come I'm seeing those things?
Health down, come on.
Aw, I was just excited for a second, I have it already.
He's greedy.
Is the guy that steals my money?
Where are you, bitch?
Who knows?
No idea.
He's somewhere.
He's there, he's doing the thing.
He be doing something.
Jesus Christ, things are moving fast.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Oh my God.
Yes.
There's something hitting me.
Oh, cool.
Let's get some buffers on that.
He's gonna hide in here.
You don't mind?
X slacks.
We got the boss located, but we also have money for the shop.
Let's go there first.
Wait, what?
Here.
Yes.
That's very good.
I'm taking that.
The razor.
You know what?
I'm gonna buy it just to see what comes after.
But I already have that, so does that mean they're gonna be quadrupled now?
I wonder.
Should I be going?
Yeah.
We have the wafer.
I think.
If there's a secret.
Here.
Holy shit.
I am on another level.
That's right, baby.
That was mostly just luck.
Okay.
If we get devil deals, we're gonna use the gift, the Rainmaker.
Don't do that.
Wait, he's dead.
Oh my god, he's dead already.
Dog food or the one that gives damage?
I think I take the one that gives damage.
Duh.
Guppy's head.
Oh!
Damage!
We take damage.
Any damage is massive right now, dude.
Like, it is going to the moon with the damage.
I don't know why we can see the map.
It's confusing.
And they're dead.
Wow.
Wait, we have...
Oh, we don't have special tears?
I thought for sure we had that at this point.
I was playing as if we had it.
Weird.
Oh, fuck!
I forgot to use the gift!
Ah, but this one is good, though.
That's a good one.
Java's...
Yeah.
Absolutely.
Dude, we can go step with this.
Dude!
Wafer!
Step!
Gimpy!
Are you seeing this?
Are you seeing what's happening?
This is a great combo.
Uh, maybe I'll use the gift in here.
Dude!
That's actually good!
The coal is good here.
Very good.
Ow!
I didn't see the...
Oh my god.
Teleport to the treasure room?
I mean, isn't that just...
What?
It could have been planetarium, I guess.
Wait, why...
Huh?
Why is that not being destroyed?
What the fuck?
That's weird.
I don't get it.
Is it because I have like a bomb modifier that...
Is it like changing it or something?
The Bible!
Bogo bombs?
Uh, wait.
I think I want this.
How come we have zero books, man?
That's kinda unbelievable.
I think I'm gonna take this.
And deck of cards is horrible.
I only have seven coins left.
I could also donate, but...
Yeah, you know what?
Why not?
Donate some money.
The thing is though...
The Bible is not really terribly useful to me right now.
Because one, I can fly already.
And two, I don't think I'm gonna have a problem against Mom.
Like, I'm gonna fucking wreck her.
Hey!
That's good.
That's nice.
Oh wait, I...
Okay, so these are blue flames.
Oh!
Huh?
I didn't see that!
Well...
Okay.
I thought we're sure something would happen there.
Oh well.
I think I'm good.
Anyway, what I was about to say is...
So, where's that other flame?
Like, there's a flame down here that I can't destroy, and it looks...
Yeah, this is not a blue flame.
What happened?
Uh...
We left behind.
I have no idea what's happening, bro.
I am so confused.
What the fuck is this?
Min, min, bi, di, di...
The belts and the screw.
We don't need more shot speed, do we?
I think we do.
Should we go crazy with the shot speed?
Uh, what's the shoot pen?
Uh, 10% chance of fire, slowing shot...
Ooh!
Wait, we have minus 9 luck!
Huh?
Oh wait, we have this too.
I don't like any of this.
I hate it.
One of these I have already.
And I have two of them.
Do I have double chance now?
I may have double chance now.
There's something about this room.
Wait a minute.
Destroy all the rocks.
Okay.
Whatever.
Let's go.
This entire run makes no sense to me.
Like, I don't even know why we're in a new run right now?
Victory lap?
Like, what does that even mean?
Like, oh, you won.
You want to do it again?
Because you're on fire right now or something?
Then I have all my items and it's kind of...
I don't know, weird?
Yo, when you die?
Okay.
Wait!
Is that the enemy that has armor?
Is that what Hakkala is for?
He seemed like an enemy that had armor.
There's just meat running around now.
Cool.
Sure.
Open up.
Oh my god, really?
Dude, I have pretty good damage.
My damage is out of control.
This is no joke.
This is no drill.
The damage is officially outside of the control zone.
Oh, god.
That's a weird attack.
So it's always like horizontally.
No, it's not.
Sometimes it is.
Hey!
Good to see you again.
It's been a while.
But I'll take this.
Three dollar bill.
Rainbow tears.
Whoa!
That could be really interesting.
If I can find it.
Isn't it just the one that makes random effects on my tears?
Random tear effects that...
yeah.
This could be really interesting.
Also, my knife is now red hot.
It's like the survival knife from Subnautica.
I need special tears.
I cannot believe I don't have that at this point.
Where's the secret there?
What the...
Sure.
Actually, if I just go like this and go up and down, I can hit the entire room.
You see that?
Shot speed is so high, I can...
shoot diagonally, like, really fast.
This is new territory.
I will say that we don't have a lot of HP for how advanced everything is.
Boss is there.
Yeah, let's go.
I'm gonna try the Bible against these.
What the hell is that?
Oh.
Bomb I can throw.
This bomb's again.
Oh wait, these guys are armored!
Oh, wait!
You need the bombs.
Oh my god.
Please stop hitting yourself.
Oh, I see, I see, you removed the armor with it.
Whoops.
That was not really my intention there.
Mort?
Yeah.
Yep.
Yep, yep, yep.
What about demons?
Do we get those?
Any demons for moi?
Okay.
Eat candy.
It's good for you.
You got blasted.
Bro got blasted!
Open.
You know what this is?
Oh my god, what was that?
Sure.
Give me more shot speed.
Special room.
Oh.
Oh my god.
The contagion.
Okay.
Damn.
This is one crazy room.
Now we're pressing gym buttons.
He just pooped out a magician.
What a trick.
Yeah, I'm kind of shooting through...
You know what's funny?
I think I... Wait, what?
Some of my shots are just straight up going through the rocks because...
I don't think the game speed can calculate it in time.
I just have too much shot speed.
That's what it feels like.
What's happening?
The compass.
I think we have that already.
Don't we have that?
Let me see through my million items.
Compass, compass, compass.
I don't think so.
Alright.
Donate some more.
The stars.
Oh.
So no planetarium.
Gotcha.
Maybe it's time to just go for the boss.
Rich!
I'm glad I didn't.
I'm glad I went here.
This way?
This is frickin' awesome.
I am so rich.
Well, not that rich, but I'm kinda rich.
That was Isaac's keys.
Not that I need any more.
Wait a sec.
I'm taking this with me.
Blew up in my face.
Oh, he did!
He did, son!
Less shot... less shot speed?
No.
Why would I... but then again, it gives me one more and fun guy.
I think I'll take it then, because of that.
Sulfur...
I kinda like the idea behind the shovel right now.
I'm taking it.
Fuck the Bible.
Fuck it.
The Bible is kinda useless to me.
We're gonna go in here.
That's right.
We're going down...
deeper.
Okay, so...
This is the floor decoration.
Yeah!
Oh, actually, we do need money.
It increases the chance of luck based...
That could be good!
That could multiply like crazy for me.
Yeah, fuck the pen.
Okay, arcade has always been good to me.
Hey, that gives me battery, right?
Oh, that's almost nothing though.
I don't know if I like that.
I have minus nine luck.
So, I don't know about this.
Never mind.
It's amazing.
Yeah?
I mean...
Dude, what does luck even affect?
I'm so confused.
I mean, other than shots.
We know it affects shots because the game tells us.
Maybe it doesn't affect us at all.
Alright, whatever.
Actually, blow this up.
And this guy as well.
Wow!
Damn.
Let's see here.
Telepathy.
Getting homing tears.
Dude, this is gonna go crazy actually.
But obviously, we're taking all three.
Dude, we're gonna be shooting double tears.
Oh no!
Oh my god!
The damage!
I'm telling you.
The telepathic bible is gonna go...
Hawkwild.
You'll see.
Let me take this though, for now.
I just wanna dig a little more.
We're not done digging.
Can I hit both?
Yes, I can.
Bro had no chance.
I'm too strong.
Okay, we can dig.
That's a flow decoration.
I was lied to.
The game lied to me.
Splits all friendly tears on screen into outward launching rings.
I'm too curious.
With this, I have to see this.
Alright.
We're keeping this item.
This item is pretty good.
Chance of fire.
Booger tears!
Oh, that's... we gotta do that.
The damage is crazy.
Fireworks!
Dude, I just need spectral tears.
That's all a man needs right now.
Are you ready for this one?
Here we go.
The heresy.
We're gonna... okay, okay.
So he does.
Boom!
It didn't do anything.
Oh, what the...
Yeah, you like damage?
You like damage, son?
You like damage?
You're done!
I need help.
And that was... that... he's dead.
He dead.
Let's go this way.
What the fuck?
No, no, no.
You're not gonna do that.
My old friend!
Nah.
I'm still not feeling it.
Not quite my tempo.
Okay.
Cry on Jax.
Eat him.
Why am I taking damage?
Yo, we can step.
We're gonna step.
We have wafer.
Like, nothing can hurt me here.
Like, I'm gonna kill whatever's gonna spawn.
Oh.
That is going to go so hard!
This candle...
is gonna catapult me into the stratosphere.
This is crazy.
Good night!
One key piece acquired.
Aw.
Keep stepping.
It is what it is.
Hey, son!
Aw, thanks.
I'm gonna go open that door.
It's happening.
The door shall be mine.
I can keep stepping.
Let me go get some HP and then step.
I'm not done stepping.
The step shall go hard.
Uh, that's good enough.
Wait, is there another heart in there?
No.
Yeah!
And I really needed that, too.
Whoa.
Hell yeah!
Dude, stepping is actually the best thing ever.
You're not even gonna give me anything.
Oh.
No, the secret rooms!
I should have gone to the secret rooms first.
Aw, man.
Yeah, wait, dark room.
Yes!
The door!
The door's open.
That book could actually go crazy.
What the hell is... I gotta take that.
This is also not bad, but I need this.
Maw of the void.
Consume thy enemy.
Huh?
How come I can't see my new items I'm getting?
Did I run out of space?
I think I can't see my items?
Oh, wait, I'm charging something.
Whoa.
Okay.
I guess that's good.
Um...
Hold on, there's a secret here.
You know what?
I'm scared.
If I leave this room, maybe this door closes.
I gotta go.
Magus Satan.
I'm gonna murder your ass.
Dude, he's gonna die.
Where is he?
Oh, he's down here.
I don't know what's going on with the... Oh my god.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Does that ring deal damage or something?
How is he not dead?
I mean, I'm doing so much damage, right?
I can't even see my character.
Wow.
Where's his HP at?
Use the Magision.
Dude,
I don't even know what's happening.
I can't tell what's mine or his.
It's all the same to me.
Yeah!
Wait, we can keep going?
I gotta open this chest, though.
Ooh, a Cecil.
It's a Cecil.
Oh my fucking god.
I don't like that.
No, I think I want you to have a good...
upbringing.
I need you to be healthy.
No PTSD, I need you to have a loving mother.
I hate that.
Oh, man.
Fucking hell.
Wait, no unlocks?
No way.
Golden god!
What?
Me, look at me.
I'm a golden god.
Okay.
Perfect time to end.
Guys, this is the first session I've had where I literally didn't lose.
I won everything I did today.
I can't believe it.
What do you say to that, huh?
That was so cool.
Oh, Tambrel, they thank you for the gifted subs.
Congrats to the people.
Pickle master Lugoli.
I feel like I've seen Lugoli before, that name.
Maybe I'm thinking of something else.
No achievements due to victory lap.
So is it just like, I guess it's just like, hey, you can run around and fuck shit up for fun, you know?
Because it did feel kind of like cheating a bit.
Because I had all the items from the start, you know?
Yeah, you can definitely use it to learn things, for sure.
Yeah.
Keep your cool build and have fun, yeah.
I mean, I'm glad I did it.
But I mean, how could I not choose that when it asked me?
I had to say yes to that.
Like, what a question.
You were saying you've seen 80% of the game, game is just starting.
See, now I know you're fucking with me.
Because that can't be.
Like, that actually cannot be.
And everyone's gonna say clueless because that's just what you do.
But it's not true.
I've played games before.
Like, I know when, you know, when I've seen a certain amount of content.
I think, I know it.
You can say that.
You're like 67%.
See, that's, I believe.
That sounds like it.
See, that's actually, I would say that's around the same percentage, I would guess.
Oh, you fucker.
Oh, you asshole.
Of course.
Depends on what your count is seeing.
Well, I'm counting like in a boring way game assets, right?
Like, I just saw like, I don't even know how many new levels today.
Like, it's got to run out of levels at some point.
There's not an infinite amount of levels.
There's not infinite amounts of items, right?
There's not infinite amounts of bosses.
You're right.
Yeah, so it's all like randomly generated or what?
Come on.
Guys, I am actually...
Okay, sure.
Maybe I'm not that far, but I don't know.
In my heart of hearts, I feel like I'm getting there, you know?
I'm not saying I'm anywhere close to being done, guys.
I'm just saying I am, you know, approaching the point where...
I can't, I'm not gonna say I've seen everything, but...
I know what the landscape looks like, you know?
And now it's about getting better in that landscape.
That's all I'm saying.
Is the landscape aware?
Is that a term?
Let's change the subject.
What did you think of the challenge run?
Wasn't that a good one?
Warm up run, and I owned it.
And then the second one, we did Magdalene.
Wait, wasn't Magdalene the second one?
The first one was...
What was the second one?
Wait, what was the second run I did?
Did I do a Stacen today?
Oh, it was Greed Magdalene, that's right!
The one that started off so bad, with no damage, and I was like on a half HP on the first floor, and then it turned into a massacre.
With the bomb laser, yes.
Oh wait, I lost, you're right!
I lost that run!
I thought I won!
Aw man, I was under the impression I only won today.
God damn, I forgot about that, that's true.
In my mind, I just thought that run was won.
Check endings.
Okay, we can check endings.
Right?
That's what I mean!
So what is this?
Uh, 6?
24, so what, that's 3 out of 24?
What is that?
I don't even know, like fucking...
There's like 8% left.
In terms of like, you know, the landscape.
That's all I'm saying.
Ending 15 is new, oh is it?
Is that something I didn't see?
No, I've seen this.
Oh, I've not seen this.
Oh my god, look at the back.
Why is mom so creepy?
Why does mom have fat legs?
I need to know.
Jesus loves me.
Can't you see?
Oh, I feel so good after that, that was a great session man.
It's kind of akin to the feeling of having a great gaming session in Starcraft 2 where you just keep winning ladder games.
It's almost like it's your whole life when you're playing Starcraft 2.
You know, your whole mood for the day is affected by it.
You eat dinner thinking, man, I killed those guys on ladder.
You know?
In Binding of Isaac, I'm gonna eat dinner, I'm gonna go to sleep, I'm gonna brush my teeth thinking, damn.
I showed mom, didn't I?
I nailed that.
That's such a good feeling.
Like it legitimately feels bad for the rest of the day.
Not like in a crazy way, but just like slightly, you know?
When you have like a shitty Isaac day.
So when you have a good day, it's like, oh yeah, best feeling.
Is that crazy?
Am I too much of a nerd?
Am I too addicted to this?
Sleeping tight after a good session, exactly.
Sometimes I dream about Isaac too, but that's normal.
Like if your brain is occupied with something, like it takes up a significant amount of your day or thinking.
You start dreaming about it.
I used to dream about World of Warcraft all the time when I was playing it.
Same here, I love video games all over, I love games.
Me too.
Games are the best.
Yeah, but it's only when you play like a lot of that game.
Like if I start a new game and play like one hour a day, I don't really dream about it.
But if it's like three or four hours a day, then I dream about it.
It's almost like there's a very precise threshold.
What if someone is out there controlling us with mouse and keyboard, you know?
And this is like the binding of Isaac of some foreign civilization.
And this is just one run.
We're all just on one run.
And when someone dies in a car accident, it's just that run ended and they're starting over somewhere.
He knows too much.
What a shitty game if that's the case.
I will say though, it has really good graphics.
I think my players should have taken Brimstone.
What would the Brimstone be in real life?
What would the equivalent be if getting an upgrade?
You know, obviously getting Steam Sale.
It's like, I don't know, winning the lottery maybe.
Finding the 99 coins is like...
Maybe that's winning the lottery, but...
Crackstone?
No, I don't mean like an actual...
It would be like some equivalent of a good buff in real life, you know?
Cure for Cancer?
Something like that.
Or an RPG?
That could work.
Steam Sale is Black Friday.
I like that, that's good.
Or maybe Steam Sale is simply Steam Sale.
You get to have a Steam Sale.
Because that's the thing.
Maybe I'll play the original Flash, Isaac, at some point.
But I'm not really motivated or interested in doing it now.
Like, I'm having fun with this.
What's Data Miner?
That's like when...
When you see something you shouldn't have seen, you know?
Like a glitch in a matrix.
The double cat that walks by, or...
The ghost in the window, the unexplained phenomena, you know?
Something like that, I guess.
Original is harder.
I can imagine.
Sometimes these old prototype games always are very difficult.
Because it's not like...
It hasn't been balanced or tuned, you know?
Data Miner is when you hit the nerve in your elbow.
Oh, that's true, that is such a weird feeling.
Or when you drop something on the floor, and it literally disappears off the face of the earth.
Like, it's not under the table, it's nowhere.
You ever had that happen?
It's like it literally faced through the floor.
That happens, and I'm losing my mind when it happens.
Like, I start screaming.
Yeah, when you drop one earb...
That happened to me once!
I was on the way home from the store, and it was at night.
So it was dark, right?
And I had a wireless earbud that I paid some money for, it was quite expensive.
And I was, you know, very happy with it, I was trying to take really good care of it.
I dropped it, and I stopped walking immediately, because it fell out of my ear, I could notice it immediately.
I spent half an hour looking for it with my flashlight on my phone.
I could not find that shit.
There was no drain, there was no drain, it was just stone, I have no idea, it just disappeared.
I never saw it again.
It's crazy.
I mean, there is a very minute minuscule chance of something facing through, you know, and tunneling.
It's just very, very unlikely, just like, you know, a glass coming together spontaneously after breaking.
Theoretically it could happen, but not really theoretically either, because the chances are just so astronomically low.
It could happen.
There's a chance.
New earbuds once have a search function, where you can get them to scream at max volume.
That's genius.
I want to customize that.
You know the meme with the old mummy?
That they extracted a voice from?
And he goes...
I want to customize my own scream.
When I saw that video for the first time, I laughed for 10 minutes straight.
It was the funniest shit.
The people who make that, man, these are the proper comedians of our time.
Where did you find the notes on the right?
Just on Google.
I just Google, like, I don't know, I forgot what I Googled, but Binding of Isaac, Concept Art, or...
Usually I also write a game name and then press kit or something.
Usually there's some good stuff in there you can use for inspiration.
Has Isaac changed your opinion on bullet hells, even if Isaac isn't that hard of a bullet hell?
It's not?
Well, then it has not changed my opinion of bullet hells.
I mean, I am learning to overcome the bullet hell in this game.
It's not a big deal anymore, as it was in the beginning, for sure.
Sometimes I get overwhelmed.
If there's a million enemies and all kinds of shit is happening, my brain just shuts down.
It happened today, with the Greed run at some point.
I just can't, you know?
But when I get into a rhythm and I start to understand, of course it gets easier, and it has gotten easier.
Your dodging on Hush was on point last stream, thank you.
I think so too.
I was in a flow state during that, for sure.
Exactly, David Dash.
These are Edmond Macmillan's own notes when he was designing the game, apparently.
Like the very earliest concept though, you know, scribbling in his notebook about ideas for a game.
Socks?
Wait, which socks?
He admits to smoking flow.
Yeah, I feel the same way, Flash.
Like, I can like or learn to love the bullet hell that is Isaac, but I don't think I'm into the genre on its own.
I think it would be too much.
Like, I don't enjoy the bullet hell for the bullet hell.
The thing I love about Isaac so much though is the variety of runs and all the crazy combinations you can get.
That's the main draw.
It's not like I go into a boss fight and go, oh shit, nice.
We got a lot of bullets now.
This is my jam, you know?
I like dodging it.
That's not really the thing.
Just the sheer variety of builds you can have and crazy stuff happening and the feeling of getting powerful.
Just that feeling of progression through each run is just so addicting.
For me.
Not gonna lie, his handwriting is pretty bad.
I don't know, I think it's decent.
I've seen way worse.
And I was grading high school papers, trust me.
There's some bad handwriting out there.
This is not one of them.
Although I've also heard that doctor's handwriting is pretty bad.
Alright, it's time for me to eat food.
Thank you for watching guys.
This was a fantastic stream.
So much stuff is happening.
New areas found, bosses defeated, challenges mastered and conquered.
Feels good man.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.
Enjoy your Sunday.